<Document>
    # Rodentia

    <Box>
        <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRodentia" Caption=""/>
    </Box>
    [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to major gameplay changes![/color]

    Rodentia are a race of humanoid beings resembling rodents. Resourceful, evasive, sneaky, but fragile.

    ## Language
    Rodentia have perfected their own tongue called [bold]Squeakish[/bold]. This allows them to communicate to each other in private.

    ## Names
    Rodentia are named with a descriptor first, followed by a more typical first name.

    ## Sounds
    Despite being the size of a dwarf, Rodentia possess the vocal cords resembling a small mouse.

    ## Nimble
    Rodentia are quite nimble and can use this to their advantage by [color=yellow]Sneaking[/color]. When [color=yellow]Sneaking[/color],
    Rodentia can move freely underneath tables where other species can't fit. They can use this to their advantage to escape from a predator,
    or hide from a pesky security officer. While underneath tables, Rodentia are limited to the actions that they can take - it's cramped down there!

    ## Mouth Storage
    Rodentia are able to put small items into their mouth for storage. This will obfuscate their speech, and if they are attacked or
    slip, the items will fall from their mouth.

    ## Diet
    Rodentia are a ravenous species, and are constantly on the hunt for food. They will often find themselves getting hungrier [bold]33% Faster[/bold] than other species.
    However, Rodentia aren't picky eaters. They can consume both raw and cooked meats, as well as food and drink containing Theobromine and Allicin, like Chocolate, Tea,
    Coffee, Onions or Garlic.

    ## Rummage
    Using their scavenging skills, Rodentia can rummage through [bold]Disposal Chutes[/bold] to find food.

    ## Mousetrap Vulnerability
    Despite being the size of a dwarf, Rodentia have always been vulnerable to mousetraps. They will trigger any mousetrap
    they step on, whether they are wearing shoes or not. Watch your step!

    ## Claw attack
    Rodentia are able to slash at others with their claws.
    These attacks deal [color=red]5[/color] points of Slash damage with a hit rate that is the same as a human's fists attack.

    ## Weapon Knockback
    Rodentia are very lightweight, and as such take so much knockback from large caliber weapons that they get pushed around.
    Rodentia also will receive [color=yellow]Stun Damage[/color] from large caliber weapons for each shot.
    In general, the weapons that will give you knockback are [color=yellow]Rifles, Sniper Rifles, Shotguns, LMGs, HMGs, and Grenade Launchers.[/color]
    Look out especially on Rocket launchers, as since they are recoil-less, you will actually get [color=red]pulled forward with the rocket[/color] for a short distance.
    The safest weapons to use that will give you no knockback are [color=green]Pistols and SMGs[/color].
    No slips can help mitigate some of the knockback from firing weapons, but not all of it!
    Also keep in mind that any stamina resistance you have DOES work to reduce the stamina damage from these weapons.

</Document>
