<Document>

  # The Basics
Roleplaying is an act of [color=#a4885c]collaborative storytelling[/color], where participants take on the role of a character in a story. You act as they would act, speak as they would speak, do what they would do. You are a writer or actor, working with other writers or actors to tell a story together.

It is important to remember that you are not your character, and nobody else is their character either. Keeping a layer of conscious separation is important for keeping In-Character (IC) and Out Of Character (OOC) apart and prevent ‘bleeding’ between. You should not act against another character just because you do not like the player behind them, and you should remember that other players are not acting against your character because they dislike you. Someone’s character not liking your character does not mean they dislike you.

Roleplay is built on this trust, it is foundational and vital for a healthy roleplay. You need to give people the benefit of the doubt and be respectful. If you think someone is blurring the lines between IC and OOC, handle it maturely, speak with them, communicate, do not accuse. It’s likely to be a misunderstanding. Otherwise, reach out to staff with a Ticket in the Discord Server. Dragging conflicts into OOC or LOOC chat will only cause more problems.

## Terms and Concepts to Know:

  - [color=#a4885c][bold]IC -[/bold][/color] In Character, something happening in universe, involving characters or the setting.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]OOC -[/bold][/color] Out of Character, something happening out of universe, involving players or the server.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Antag -[/bold][/color] Antagonists, roles some players are given depending on various conditions that act against the station and its crew. Often featuring objectives to steal valuable items, sabotage systems, or kill specific crew members.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]NRP -[/bold][/color] No Roleplay, or no consideration or attempt to RP.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]LRP -[/bold][/color] Low Roleplay, minimum consideration or attempt to RP.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]MRP -[/bold][/color] Medium Roleplay, Roleplaying but still adhering to the chaotic nature of SS14. Starlight is a Medium Roleplay Server.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]HRP -[/bold][/color] High Roleplay, acting very seriously and often in the case of HRP servers with minimum antags or chaos, treated more like a life simulator.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Meta -[/bold][/color] OOC information, often in the context of Metagaming. Metagaming is when meta OOC information is used IC or influences IC actions, which is usually bad.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Powergaming -[/bold][/color] Focusing on pure mechanics for an advantage, beyond what makes sense IC. Has some overlap with Meta, as mechanics and how the game functions are inherently Meta, so leveraging that knowledge for an advantage to powergame overlaps.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Yes And -[/bold][/color] An improvisation technique. The idea is to always build on what other people are doing, not just shut it down. The Clown has taken the HoP’s dog Ian hostage! Yes, and it's Ian’s birthday today too, oh the humanity!
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]SSD -[/bold][/color] Space Sleep Disorder. Visualized by green ZZZ… appearing over a character, this means they disconnected or crashed. In universe, to help explain this away, Cryosleep sometimes causes Space Sleep Disorder and SSD people should just be propped in a chair.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Space Lag -[/bold][/color] Space Lag. An IC way to explain lag. Our stations sit near the Nullscar, and waves of Temporal Flux from it can cause oddities. Sometimes called Cryo Sickness or FTL Sickness.
  - [color=#a4885c][bold]Try Hard -[/bold][/color] Trying to win or be optimal, often at the expense of the RP experience of themselves and others. While not strictly against the rules, it can border on Powergaming. See ‘[textlink="Losing Is Fun" link="RoleplayGuide03"]’ for more information.

</Document>
