<Document>

  # Collaborative Storytelling
Collaborative Storytelling is a way of telling a story that is popular in TV or Comics with a shared world with a large cast of characters, with each character’s story often being told by a handful of writers but all crossing over and interacting with the wider shared world. [color=#a4885c]All Roleplay is inherently Collaborative Storytelling.[/color]

One of the greatest things about Roleplay as a Storytelling Medium, is that while other stories have to put in endless amounts of legwork to upkeep the illusion that the world keeps moving beyond the view of the main characters or the camera, in Roleplay this is by default true. There is no one perspective or one main character, everyone is the audience and perspective of their own character’s story. This means that these stories all continue at all times just out of sight of one another, and often overlap and impact one another in an organic and ‘real’ way.

This of course can cause tensions however. Any story can impact any other story at any moment, and this is something to be mindful of because the impact you have on someone else’s story might not be one they expect, or like. This is why it’s important to remember that [color=#a4885c]IC and OOC are not the same[/color]. There should be no ill will between players because of these moments, and ill will should not be assumed as the motivator of them either.

At the end of the day, everyone is just trying to tell a fun story and be entertained. We have to [color=#a4885c]respect[/color] one another’s stories, and [color=#a4885c]trust[/color] each other to not be trying to intentionally sabotage them. We are collaborating, not competing. [italic]The only way to ‘win’ in Roleplay is to experience fun Roleplay.[/italic]

In order to maintain this, it’s often healthy to check in on other players OOC after intense scenes and just chat about how cool a scene or moment was, or how unfortunate it was that events just didn’t pan out in a character’s favor, etc. While not necessary, it helps to shore up any hurt feelings or doubts about each other’s motivations, and creates a healthier RP space for everyone.

</Document>
