<Document>
  # Reagent Flow
  Understanding how reagents move through plumbing networks is key to building efficient factories.

  ## Networks
  A [color=#a4885c]plumbing network[/color] is a group of machines and ducts connected together through their connectors. Reagents can only flow between machines on the [bold]same[/bold] network.

  Each [color=#ff5959]inlet[/color] connector on a machine forms its own [bold]independent network[/bold]. This means if a machine has multiple inlet connectors, each one connects to a separate network. Pipes attached to different inlets on the same machine [bold]do not bridge[/bold].

  [color=#5999ff]Outlet[/color] connectors on the other hand, [bold]share[/bold] a single network. A tank with three outlet connectors merges all three into one network, so any machine pulling from any of those sides sees the same pool of reagents. This can be used to save space and simplify layouts.

  ## Pull-Based Flow
  Plumbing uses a [color=#a4885c]pull-based[/color] model, reagents don't flow on their own. A machine with an inlet [bold]actively pulls[/bold] reagents from the outlets of other machines on the same network. If nothing is pulling, nothing moves.

  This means:
  - An [color=#a4885c]Input[/color] won't push reagents anywhere by itself. Another machine must pull from it.
  - A [color=#a4885c]Synthesizer[/color] generates reagents into its buffer, but they sit there until something pulls.
  - A [color=#a4885c]Tank[/color] pulls from its inlet network and stores reagents. Other machines then pull from the tank's outlet network.

  ## Round-Robin Distribution
  When a machine pulls reagents and there are [bold]multiple outlets[/bold] on the same network (e.g., two synthesizers feeding a tank), it uses round-robin distribution. Each update tick, it starts pulling from a different outlet, cycling through them fairly.

  ## Transfer Rate
  Each machine pulls a fixed amount per update tick ([color=#a4885c]20u[/color] every 2 seconds). This transfer budget is shared across all of the machine's inlets, a machine with four inlet connectors still pulls 20u total per tick, not 20u per inlet.

  ## Reactor: Targeted Pulling
  The [color=#a4885c]Reactor[/color] is special, it pulls [bold]specific reagents[/bold] rather than everything. It fills each target reagent fully before moving to the next. If you set targets of 30u Iron and 20u Carbon, it will pull all 30u of Iron first, then pull Carbon.

  ## Filter: Selective Routing
  The [color=#a4885c]Filter[/color] has one inlet and two outlets. It pulls everything from the inlet network into its buffer, then when other machines pull from it, the filter controls which reagents are available on which outlet:
  - [bold]Filtered outlet[/bold]: Only provides the reagents you've selected.
  - [bold]Passthrough outlet[/bold]: Only provides reagents you [italic]haven't[/italic] selected.

  ## Pill Press: Mixing Mode
  In [color=#a4885c]mixing mode[/color], the pill press ignores its main inlet and instead pulls from its [color=#59e659]mixing inlets[/color]. Each mixing inlet pulls from its own separate network into a staging area. Once both staging areas have enough reagent, they combine and press a pill at the configured ratio.

  ## Tips
  - Place [color=#a4885c]Tanks[/color] between production and consumption to buffer reagents and decouple supply from demand.
  - Use the [color=#a4885c]plunger[/color] to clear stuck reagents from any machine's buffer.
  - Machines only pull when they have space in their buffer. A full buffer stops pulling until reagents are pulled from it.
</Document>
