<Document>
  # Plumbing
  Plumbing is a reagent piping system that lets you build fluid supply systems and automated chemical factories. Fluid ducts connect machines together into networks, moving reagents between them without manual intervention.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RPLD" Caption="RPLD"/>
  </Box>

  ## Getting Started
  Plumbing is built using the [color=#a4885c]RPLD[/color] (Rapid Plumbing Device), which works like an RCD but for plumbing. It can place fluid ducts and all plumbing machines (but not all machines with plumbing connectors). Select what to build from its radial menu.

  All plumbing machines and ducts are [color=#a4885c]rotatable[/color]. Use the rotation key before or after placing to orient inlets and outlets correctly. Machines must be oriented so their connectors line up with adjacent ducts. Most plumbing machines are rotatable while anchored.

  ## Fluid Ducts
  Fluid ducts are pipes that carry reagents between machines. They similar to atmos pipes, place them with the RPLD and they automatically connect to adjacent ducts and machines to form a [color=#a4885c]plumbing network[/color]. Ducts hide under floor tiles. There are four variants:

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookPlumbingDuctStraight" Caption="Straight"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookPlumbingDuctBend" Caption="Bend"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookPlumbingDuctTJunction" Caption="T-Junction"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GuidebookPlumbingDuctFourway" Caption="Fourway"/>
  </Box>

  ## Connector Colors
  Each machine's connectors are color-coded:
  - [color=#ff5959]Red[/color] connectors are [bold]inlets[/bold]: the machine pulls reagents from the network through these.
  - [color=#5999ff]Blue[/color] connectors are [bold]outlets[/bold]: other machines can pull reagents from this machine through these.
  - [color=#59e659]Green[/color] connectors are [bold]mixing inlets[/bold]: specialized inlets for ratio-controlled mixing (pill press).

  Connected connectors appear as smooth joints. Disconnected connectors appear jagged.

  ## Plunger
  Most machines with internal buffers are [color=#a4885c]plungeable[/color]. Use a plunger on them to flush their contents onto the floor. Useful for clearing stuck reagents.

  ## Reagent Flow
  See [textlink="Reagent Flow" link="PlumbingFlow"] for details on how reagents move through networks, pull mechanics, and distribution.

  ## Machines
  See [textlink="Plumbing Machines" link="PlumbingMachines"] for details on each machine.

</Document>
