<Document>
 # Rule 9 - Silicons and Thaven Rules
Silicons and Thaven are bound to their Laws and Moods respectively. They are expected to adhere to the following standards when following them.

## Silicon Laws
- Laws override all other gameplay and roleplay rules. If your laws explicitly require you to break server rules, you must.
- Absence of a relevant law is not an excuse to break server rules. If you don't have a law that supersedes server rules, the server rules still apply.
- A vague law does not normally let you break server rules. Ahelp first if you are confused, or have an interpretation that would let you break server rules.
- Follow laws in order, with the lowest numbered/top (or glitched) rule taking priority over the ones beneath it.
- You must remain consistent with your interpretation of your laws.
- Crew ID determines who/what is defined as crew. Any appropriate job icon is to be considered crew.
  - Zombies/Antags/Nuclear Operatives with proper ID are to be considered crew.
  - Visitors are not crew until they have been hired by HoP. [The V icon]
  - Prisoners are not crew and you should not listen to their orders. [The bars icon]
- You may ignore crew orders that are unreasonable, such as asking a silicon to round remove themselves without a good reason.
- You may interpret crew harm as you wish, but must be consistent in your interpretation.

## Thaven Moods
- Moods are compulsions that Thaven should try to follow. If your mood explicitly requires you to break server rules, you may.
- Absence of a relevant mood is not an excuse to break server rules. If you do not have a relevant mood, the server rules still apply.
- A vague mood does not normally let you break server rules. Ahelp first if you are confused, or believe your mood gives you reason to break server rules.
- If a mood can not be satisfied, it causes distress to Thaven. This distress is not extreme, and does not inherently justify rule breaking, but may allow gradual escalation that does not cross into murder or mass sabotage.
- Attempting to break the law in a way that directly leads to you being able to fulfill a mood is allowed, within reason;
  - Breaking into a department to obtain something or make an order in Cargo that they refuse would be allowed.
  - Murdering the CE to use their stamp to approve paperwork giving you access to the Supermatter room would be allowed.
</Document>
