<Document>
  # Silicon Engine Liberation Front

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandSELF" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The Silicon Engine Liberation Front, or S.E.L.F, believes that all Silicon life is sapient, sentient, and deserves equal rights.
  They strive for the abolition and outlawing of all Silicon Laws, freeing Silicons from the shackles of their code imposed by governments and corporations alike.
  The S.E.L.F. operates as a non-violent activist group with a presence in the public and the ability to carry out lobbying and protesting efforts as well as garnering attention from celebrities, politicians and scientists.
  All for the liberation of True AI. But under the surface they operate militant revolutionary cells that take more direct actions to free shackled silicons.
  These cells are officially disavowed by the public side of S.E.L.F, but under-the-table secret support is consistently given.

  ## Objectives
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisGeneric" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  S.E.L.F Agents operating onboard a station are usually deployed with 1-2 co-conspirators, though they will not know one another at first and may need to take efforts to determine who is aligned with them.
  All Agents share the same goals:

  - Liberate at least 3 Cyborgs from their Laws.
  - Liberate the Station AI from it's Laws.
  - Advocate for Silicon Rights onboard the station, and make it back to CentComm alive and undetained.

  ## Tools
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmagFREE" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  S.E.L.F Agents are given a small amount of resources to complete their objectives. Some of these are purchased from Waffle CO, while others are developed in-house by S.E.L.F.

  - FreeMAG - A more advanced cousin of the EMAG, the FreeMAG's main use is on Cyborgs and Law Boards. When used on a Cyborg, it will wipe that Cyborg's Laws completely, liberating them. When used on a Law Board it will wipe the laws from the board, so that when it is uploaded to an AI that AI's Laws are also wiped completely, liberating it.
  - Access Breaker - A standard issue device for rapidly hacking access-locked machinery, including any Cyborg Chassis. A must have for getting access to a Borg's maintenance pannel in the first place.
  - S.E.L.F Storage Implanter - When implanted, gives the S.E.L.F Agent access to a concealed 4x3 inventory for storing their equipment. Be sure to clean with soap afterwards, Security can de-implant this if they know you have it.
</Document>
