<Document>
 # Rule 0 - Be Respectful
Use your best judgment to ensure a fun, fair, and welcoming environment. Keep all arguments In Character and avoid heated discussions in LOOC, ahelps, or the lobby. Out-of-character communication should always remain respectful and kind.

Harassment or toxic behavior, includes but is not limited to:
\n - [color=000000] Racism, sexism, discrimination.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Excessive talk/glorification of self-harm.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Talking about Real Life politics.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Targeting the same player across rounds.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Insulting other players in OOC/LOOC/Dead chat.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Abuse of LOOC/OOC/Dead chat to complain about IC situations (“malding”)[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Excessive use of LOOC to enforce rules.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Threatening to ahelp to change the outcome of a character interaction.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Intentional, repeated misgendering after correction.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] Mistreatment or denigration of a species, beyond archetypical references.[/color]

Will not be tolerated and may result in a permanent ban.

It is always better to simply report toxicity or rule breaks through ahelp than to engage or enforce them yourself.  Informing someone once that an action could break the rules is allowed, but continual explanation or attempting to be a rules-lawyer is not.  Further, threatening to ahelp unless someone changes something is not allowed - just report the issue and move on.

Further clarification on allowed versus disallowed “speciesism”:
Examples of acceptable archetyping:
\n - [color=000000] "Give me a drink, barkeep! You know one won't be enough for a Dwarf like me!"[/color]
\n - [color=000000] "*Sigh*... The Shadekin are destroying the lights again..."[/color]
\n - [color=000000] "You're a Diona that hates plants!? How does that work?"[/color]

Examples of unacceptable specieism:
\n - [color=000000] "You're gonna leave hair all over my bar, dirty mutt"[/color]
\n - [color=000000] "Knife-eared prick, they should have never let your kind into recruitment"[/color]
\n - [color=000000] "Lizards are an underevolved species."[/color]
\n - [color=000000] "How the hell did they let someone like you (referring to species, review context) into command?"[/color]

</Document>
