<Document>
  # Rule 12 - Silicons and Thaven Rules
[bold]Silicons[/bold] and [bold]Thaven[/bold] are bound to their Laws and Moods respectively. They are expected to adhere to the following standards when following them.

  ## Silicon Laws

- Laws override all other gameplay and roleplay rules. If your laws explicitly require you to break server rules, you must.
\n - [color=000000]Absence of a relevant law is not an excuse to break server rules. If you don't have a law that supersedes server rules, the server rules still apply.
\n - [color=000000]A vague law does not normally let you break server rules. Ahelp first if you are confused, or have an interpretation that would let you break server rules.
- Follow laws in order, with the lowest numbered/top (or glitched) rule taking priority over the ones beneath it.
- You cannot request a law change, or willingly allow an unauthorized law change.
\n - [color=000000]Authorized law changes are to be allowed as long as consistent with your laws.
\n - [color=000000]Authorized law changes can be found in the Command SOP.
\n - [color=000000]Lethal force may be used in the case of unauthorized law changes.
- You must remain consistent with your interpretation of your laws/moods.
- Crew ID determines who/what is defined as crew. Any appropriate job icon is to be considered crew.
\n - [color=000000]Zombies/Antags/Nuclear Operatives with proper ID are to be considered crew.
\n - [color=000000][bold]Visitors are not crew[/bold] until they have been hired by HoP. [The V icon]
\n - [color=000000][bold]Prisoners are not crew[/bold] and you should not listen to their orders [The bars icon]
- Crew harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood.
- You may ignore crew orders that are unreasonable, such as asking a silicon to round remove themselves without a good reason.

  ## Thaven Moods

- Moods are compulsions that Thaven should try to follow. If your mood [color=#ff0000]explicitly[/color] requires you to break server rules, you may.
\n - Absence of a relevant mood is not an excuse to break server rules. If you do not have a relevant mood, the server rules still apply.
\n - A vague mood does not normally let you break server rules. Ahelp first if you are confused, or believe your mood gives you reason to break server rules.
- If a mood can not be satisfied, it causes distress to Thaven. This distress is not extreme, and does no inherently justify rule breaking, but may allow gradual escalation that does not cross into murder or mass sabotage.
- Attempting to break the law in a way that directly leads to you being able to fulfill a mood may be allowed, within reason;
\n - Breaking into a department to obtain something or make an order in Cargo that they refuse would be allowed.
\n - Murdering the Chief Engineer to use their stamp to approve paperwork giving you access to a room in Engineering would not be allowed.
- Some leniency for Rule 13 may be allowed based on mood, but those who have been hired to Command, Security, and NanoTrasen jobs on stations are expected to be experienced in their work, meaning they have earned this rank while managing their moods for potentially years. They should understand how to juggle the responsibilities of their jobs with the fickle and often arbitrary compulsions of their moods in a way that would not get them fired.

</Document>