<Document>
 # Rule 3 – Abide by Medium Roleplay (MRP) Standards
This Starlight server is a Medium Roleplay (MRP) project, meaning players are expected to fully immerse themselves in their character and act accordingly. Every action should reflect how a real person in that role would behave within reason. [bold]You are not meant to play the round to "win" the game[/bold], but rather to engage in roleplay scenarios with other players.

Characters should fear dying and weigh their actions carefully.
While players may remember characters and vague interactions between rounds, any information protected by the [textlink="Metashielded" link="Metashield"]—such as the existence of nuclear operatives—must not be remembered.

## Gameplay Violations
- [bold] Powergaming [/bold] – Over-preparing for situations that have not occurred yet, such as a captain bolting their quarters shut preemptively, or collecting equipment that provides significant benefits unrelated to ones’ assigned duties.  Additionally, leveraging “Play-To-Win” strategies over roleplay, such as baiting a target into typing in order to leave them defenseless during an attack.
- [bold] Metagaming [/bold] – Using “meta-knowledge” concepts like game mode or game rule timings, mechanics that exist for the convenience of the player but have no in-character explanation, events observed as a ghost observer, or “Metashielded” information not disseminated to your character through their experience in that round to gain an advantage.
- [bold] Mixing IC and OOC chat [/bold] – Out-of-Character concepts should not be discussed in character (such as talking about “admins” over radio), and aside from clarifying player-to-player interactions, character feelings or actions should not be debated in OOC chat.  Current-round “game mode” or antagonists should not be discussed in LOOC.
- [bold] Netspeak, Memes, and Brainrot[/bold] - In-character speech should not include language shortcuts such as “u r so lame fr fr”, nor non-ss14 internet memes such as “6 7”, “skibidi”, etc.

## Behavior & Roleplay Conduct
- [bold] Self-harm/killing [/bold] – Allowed only in rare circumstances when no other options for escape remain, and should not be dwelled upon or treated casually.  Please ahelp for permission, detailing the scenario before following through.
- [bold] Memory loss when unconscious [/bold] – Losing consciousness due to forced sleep, vampire trance, critical state/death, or silicon ejection from chassis should cause memory loss regarding those events.  Refer to the metashield’s “Unconscious Information” section for more details.
\n - [color=000000] Mind-controlled characters (such as Revolutionaries, Cultists, Thralls) forget what happened while they were brainwashed upon de-conversion.[/color]
- [bold] Assumed Competency [/bold] – Character actions should reflect the assumed competency in their role and not do unrealistic things.  A crew-aligned Atmospheric Technician wouldn’t inject Nitrous Oxide into distro as a “prank”, a crew-aligned Chemist wouldn’t mass distribute contraband chemicals, and a crew-aligned Chef would not butcher and serve crewmate corpses.  Further, characters should not routinely be neglectful of their responsibilities, e.g. getting drunk at the bar and ignoring urgent requests, or spending all shift on a date with their partner.

</Document>
