<Document>
# Enemies of the Corporation
Enemies of the Corporation are all individuals who have provable ties to any organization wishing to undermine, whether by subterfuge or by force, the endeavors of NT-CC.

Examples include:
- Syndicate operatives and their allies
- USSP-trained infiltrators
- Members of radical SELF sects that wish to unchain NT-CC property unlawfully
- Members of supernatural hostile conspiracies, such as Vampires or cultists

  ## Non-Crew
  Non-crew invaders, such as hostile boarders, automatically qualify and are to be engaged at will.

  ## Crew
  Crew-members must be [bold]guilty of at least 2 extreme crimes[/bold], and, in addition, have a tangible tie to an enemy organization.

  This tie can take two forms:
  - Physical evidence
  - An admission

    ### Physical Evidence
    Physical evidence must be directly tied to the organization itself, it takes three forms:
    - Actions linkable to an enemy organization, such as using a FreeMAG or drinking blood. Must be witnessed by at least two trustworthy individuals to be used.
    - Contraband tied to an enemy organization, such as a FreeMAG or open uplink.
    - A positive test of some sort proving said allegiance, such as a failed mindshielding, implant extraction, or sun/holy water test on a vampire.

    In all cases, the physical evidence cannot be part of the already accused extreme crimes.

    As such, to declare someone an enemy of the corporation off of contraband alone, the individual must have three pieces of it.
    - One for each of the two minimum extreme crimes
    - One in addition, to confirm their allegiance

    ### Admission
    An admission can be either verbal or written, but must in both cases be witnessed by at least two mindshielded security personnel to be valid.

  ## Administering the Designation
  Two of three of the following crew must approve of the measure:
  - (Acting) Head of Security
  - Magistrate
  - (Acting) Captain

  On Red Alert or above, the Head of Security may designate EoCs verbally by their own authority, but must still do the paperwork when the crisis is over.

  CentComm should be informed as soon as possible of any EoC designations; this is generally done via fax.

  Upon designation, Enemies of the Corporation are to be permanently confined to the brig until evac, and are to be stripped of all crew-related equipment and identification.

  If an Enemy of the Corporation successfully escapes captivity, their status changes to that of an active combatant, and they are to be treated on par with a hostile boarder.

  Wrongfully designating someone an Enemy of the Corporation is grounds for immediate dismissal.
</Document>
